<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Yoga Fitness</string>
    <string name="title_workout">Workout</string>
    <string name="title_excercises">Excersices</string>
    <string name="title_utilities">Utility</string>
    <string name="title_tips">Tips</string>

    <string name="q">Prepare</string>
    <string name="w">Identify A Comfortable Space</string>
    <string name="e">Wear Comfortable Clothing</string>
    <string name="r">Plan Smart Goals</string>
    <string name="t">Practice Regularly</string>
    <string name="y">Switch Off Any Distractions</string>
    <string name="u">Start With The Basics</string>
    <string name="i">Practice Yoga On An Empty Stomach</string>
    <string name="o">Always Warm Up At The Beginning</string>
    <string name="p">Go Slow</string>
    <string name="a">Breathe Right</string>
    <string name="s">Always Cool Down At The End</string>
    <string name="d">Pranayama</string>
    <string name="f">Flexibility</string>
    <string name="g">Learn From The Experts</string>

    <string name="q1">The first thing you need to do is read about yoga, research about the different asanas, and their benefits and styles. Read the guidelines and check out the pictures to learn the correct postures. Get your comfy yoga clothes and a non-slipping, comfortable yoga mat. Try to practice yoga in the open air. Ensure not to eat anything 4 hours before doing yoga. It is best to practice yoga in the morning.
</string>
    <string name="w1">Yoga calls for a space that is well lit and properly ventilated. It helps if the setting is serene as maximum benefits from yoga can be reaped when performed in a soothing environment. Add candles to light up your room, in case the room is not sufficiently lit. Ensure that there are no sharp objects or furniture around you, as they could cause injuries when stretching during the asanas.
</string>
    <string name="e1">It is very important to wear clothing that is comfortable while you perform yoga. A relaxed track pant with a loose-fitting tee is a great option for many. You can also choose from the numerous attires that are available in the market these days. The key is to opt for designs that let you breathe and for materials that absorb sweat along the way.</string>
    <string name="r1">Identify your goals before you start practicing. Chart out a plan for yourself and make sure that it is specific, measurable, achievable, reliable, and timely. Be reasonable in your expectations and bear in mind that yoga is not meant for achieving physical benefits only.</string>
    <string name="t1">The ideal time to practice yoga is early in the morning before the sun rises or in the evening after the sun sets. Decide on a time that is most suited to you and devote that time in its entirety to yoga every day. Resolve to practice yoga every day. Yes, every day, even if you do it just for 20 minutes. Further, resolve to try a new posture every week. This way will not only make you become more adept at the yoga, but also make you learn more poses.</string>
    <string name="y1">Do not multitask while practicing yoga at home. Those endless chores, phone calls, and the lure of social networking sites can wait for a more suitable time. Your sole focus while practicing yoga must be on your goals and the asanas that you perform. The slightest carelessness can at times result in grave injuries.</string>
    <string name="u1">Start your practice with very basic yoga postures if you are a complete beginner. Like, start with basic seated postures, such as Sukhasana, Vajrasana, and stretches like Balasana and Pawanmuktasana. You need to slowly acquaint yourself with the yogic practice. So, it is better to slowly open your body to the restorative postures and then move forward.</string>
    <string name="i1">Yoga at home can be practiced at a time of your convenience. However, never practice yoga as soon as you consume a meal. It is ideal to wait for at least a couple of hours after breakfast/lunch or for four hours after dinner before you start your practice session.</string>
    <string name="o1">As with other forms of fitness, it is mandatory that you indulge in some form of warm up exercises before you get into the more intricate yoga asanas. Warming up aids in preparing the body for the rigors ahead, thus protecting it from injuries.</string>
    <string name="p1">Yoga is meant to nourish your body and soul and to help you lead a calmer and more fulfilling life. Respect your body and give it sufficient time to adjust to the practice. Practicing yoga even for a few minutes every day stretches your body in new ways and therefore it is crucial not to rush through the asanas in a bid to finish early. Listen to your body and increase the time and repetition of each asana accordingly. Doing so is sure to keep injuries at bay.</string>
    <string name="a1">It is essential to breathe right when practicing the asanas. Hold your breath only when it is specified. Shortness of breath is your body’s way of asking you to slow down. This is the most important tip in yoga for beginners at home.</string>
    <string name="s1">Just like warming up is essential to awaken your muscles at the start of a session, cooling down is equally crucial to calm down the rejuvenated muscles at the end of the session. Always wrap up your yoga session with Savasana. This asana is designed to help the body unwind and to restore your breathing and augmented blood circulation back to normalcy.</string>
    <string name="d1">Pranayama, like Kapalbhati, Anulom-Vilom, Bhramri, teaches breath-control. Yoga is all about the breath; your breathing is as important as the correct postures. Keeping pranayama’s myriad of benefits aside, it also helps in learning how to control and regularize your breathing. So, start practicing pranayama regularly even before you start practicing Yogasanas.</string>
    <string name="f1">Flexibility is one feature of yoga that scares a lot of people away and confuses the rest. You are not supposed to be super flexible to be able to do yoga. It is actually one of the ways that yoga benefits you – it makes your body more flexible and limber. So, the first thing you should do in the morning when you wake up is doing some basic stretches and twists to improve your flexibility. But keep in mind this is a slow process.</string>
    <string name="g1">Yes, I said experts, and you don’t need to leave your home to do that. I am a big fan of workout DVDs. There are DVDs for complete beginners that will help you in learning the correct postures for different poses. At the same time, the DVDs will give you a nice workout. </string>


    <string name="x1">Utkatasana</string>
    <string name="x2">Garudasana</string>
    <string name="x3">Utthita Parsvakonasana</string>
    <string name="x4">Parighasana</string>
    <string name="x5">Natarajasana</string>
    <string name="x6">Adho Mukha Svanasana</string>
    <string name="x7">Tadasana</string>
    <string name="x8">Urdhva Prasarita Eka Padasana</string>
    <string name="x9">Vrksasana</string>
    <string name="x10">Anjaneyasana</string>
    <string name="x11">Bharadvajasana I</string>
    <string name="x12">Ardha Matsyendrasana</string>
    <string name="x13">Marichyasana III</string>
    <string name="x14">Parivrtta Parsvakonasana</string>
    <string name="x15">Parivrtta Janu Sirsasana</string>
    <string name="x16">Paschimottanasana</string>
    <string name="x17">Janu Sirsasana</string>
    <string name="x18">Upavistha Konasana</string>
    <string name="x19">Dhanurasana</string>
    <string name="x20">Urdhva Dhanurasana</string>
    <string name="x21">Urdhva Mukha Svanasana</string>
    <string name="x22">Tolasana</string>
    <string name="x23">Eka Pada Koundinyanasana II</string>
    <string name="x24">Kapotasana</string>
    <string name="x25">Bhujangasana</string>
    <string name="x26">Virasana</string>
    <string name="x27">Bitilasana</string>
    <string name="x28">Dandasana</string>
    <string name="x29">Purvottanasana</string>
    <string name="x30">Ustrasana</string>


</resources>
